<book>
  <title>How the Bible Actually Works: In which I Explain how an Ancient, Ambiguous, and Diverse Book Leads us to Wisdom rather than Answers - and why that’s Great News</title>
  <authors>Peter Enns</authors>
  <highlights>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>To say the Bible is ancient might seem mundane and unnecessary to point out, but I find the opposite is true. The Bible, because it is a constant companion of faith, is often thought of as “God’s personal love letter to me” or the like. But that familiarity risks obscuring how old the Bible really is.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B07R7QRGCY&amp;location=131">131</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>The writers of the Bible lived long ago and far away, intent on asking their questions and seeking their answers, oblivious to our own questions and concerns. Now this may seem as if the Bible is locked forever in its ancient moment, but that is most definitely not true. As we will see, the Bible’s antiquity shows us the need to ponder God anew in our here and now. Indeed, it gives us permission to do so.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B07R7QRGCY&amp;location=145">145</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>As we will see later in the book, Jews and Christians throughout history have always known that this ancient Bible cannot simply be “followed” like a recipe. It takes creative imagination to bridge the ancient and modern horizons. And, as we will see in due course, that process is already happening—I can’t stress this enough—within the pages of the Bible itself.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B07R7QRGCY&amp;location=151">151</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>when reading the Bible for spiritual guidance, we find we are usually left to work things out for ourselves at the end of the day. This isn’t a drawback or a problem. This is by design. And the thing is, the need to work things out has always been the case, ever since there has been a Bible. So instead of being fed up and frustrated with a Bible that refuses to tell us clearly what to do, maybe we should step back and ask why this is so and what benefit we might derive from it.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B07R7QRGCY&amp;location=159">159</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>So instead of going though painful intellectual contortions pretending this diversity does not exist in the Bible, we should ask why there is so much of it and how this might actually be good news for us.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B07R7QRGCY&amp;location=169">169</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>I believe that God knows best what sort of sacred writing we need. And these three characteristic ways the Bible behaves, rather than posing problems to be overcome, are telling us something about how the Bible actually works and therefore what the Bible’s true purpose is—and the need to align our expectations with it.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B07R7QRGCY&amp;location=173">173</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>Rather than providing us with information to be downloaded, the Bible holds out for us an invitation to join an ancient, well-traveled, and sacred quest to know God, the world we live in, and our place in it. Not abstractly, but intimately and experientially. A quest—meaning this is going to take some time and effort. No “Have a Great Spiritual Life in Five Easy Steps!” pamphlet. The Bible isn’t just going to hand us the goods.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B07R7QRGCY&amp;location=179">179</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>The Bible becomes a confusing mess when we expect it to fulfill some other purpose—like functioning as an owner’s manual for faith. But when we allow the Bible to determine our expectations, we see that intending to gain wisdom is our proper spiritual posture toward it.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B07R7QRGCY&amp;location=211">211</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>Wisdom is about the lifelong process of being formed into mature disciples, who wander well along the unscripted pilgrimage of faith, in tune to the all-surrounding thick presence of the Spirit of God in us and in the creation around us.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B07R7QRGCY&amp;location=214">214</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>If God were a helicopter parent, our sacred book would be full of clear, consistent, unambiguous information to take in. In other words, it wouldn’t look anything like it does. But if the Bible’s main purpose is to form us, to grow us to maturity, to teach us the sacred responsibility of communing with the Spirit by walking the path of wisdom, it would leave plenty of room for pondering, debating, thinking, and the freedom to fail. And that is what it does.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B07R7QRGCY&amp;location=259">259</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>Seeing the Bible as a source of godly wisdom to be explored, pondered, deliberated, and put into action will free us of a common burden so many Christians have unwittingly carried, namely, that watching over us is God, an unstable parent, who is right off the bat harsh, vindictive, at best begrudgingly merciful, and mainly interested in whether we’ve read and understood the fine print; if not, God has no recourse but to punish us.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B07R7QRGCY&amp;location=284">284</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>Play travel soccer?</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B07R7QRGCY&amp;location=383">383</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>Reading the book of Proverbs on child rearing is like paying good money for financial advice and being told after ten sessions, “Here’s what I’ve come up with. Invest your money wisely, and you will be set for retirement.” I was hoping for stock tips.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B07R7QRGCY&amp;location=385">385</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>Or perhaps we readers are meant to insert “generally speaking” and then figure things out on our own as situations come up—in other words, to be wise. That’s what I think.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B07R7QRGCY&amp;location=402">402</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>If someone has a stubborn and rebellious son, . . . his father and his mother . . . shall say to the elders of his town, “This son of ours is stubborn and rebellious. He will not obey us. He is a glutton and a drunkard.” Then all the men of the town shall stone him to death. (Deut. 21:18–21)</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B07R7QRGCY&amp;location=411">411</location>
    </highlight>
  </highlights>
</book>